Joel Rivera

Senior Front-End Engineer

407-994-8118 / joelrivera.me@gmail.com

Skills

React (Expert)



TypeScript (Expert)



Next.js (Expert)



Tailwindcss (Experienced)



AI-powered UI (Expert)



Web Accessibility (Skillful)



Links

My Website

GitHub

LinkedIn

Languages

English (Native)



Spanish (Native)



Professional summary

Senior Front-End Engineer with 9 years of experience in building modern web applications. Highly attentive to details, self-motivated, and a problem-solver. Excels in creating user-friendly and visually appealing web interfaces that make for great user experiences.

Employment history

Development Lead, Endava

AUG, 2021 - PRESENT, REMOTE

- Led a high impact front-end unit testing initiative to define and establish testing best practices, and documentation. Increased code coverage from 0% to ~ 10% resulting in a higher quality and stable code base.
- Led an initiative to identify and rectify web accessibility vulnerabilities on the Endava website, and cultivated awareness by conducting an web accessibility 101 lunch and learn session focusing on awareness, importance, and practicality.

Senior Front-End Engineer, IBM

MAY, 2015 - FEB, 2021, NEW YORK CITY

- On the IBM DTE Solutions team, I designed and built flagship product demos for several Watson APIs like Watson Speech to Text, Watson NLU, and Watson Assistant, which helped IBM win over \$6 million in revenue from new client engagements.
- On the IBM Watson Prototypes team, I built Watson AI-powered user interfaces and interactive experiences for high profile clients like Starbucks, Geico, CNN, and Morgan Stanley.

Front-End Developer, Morgan Stanley

FEB, 2014 - DEC, 2014, NEW YORK CITY

- Developed user-friendly front-end interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to enhance the user experience and meet the business requirements of Morgan Stanley's financial services applications.
- Built internal microsites, published quarterly earnings reports, and maintained morganstanley.com in production.

Education

Self-Taught Education

FEB, 2012 - PRESENT, REMOTE

I transitioned into a career in design and engineering through self-directed learning rather than a conventional Computer Science degree. My technical proficiency was honed through a combination of online educational platforms such as Pluralsight (formerly Code School), Codecademy, Treehouse, CSS Tricks, and MDN, along with practical experience gained from developing websites for local clients and engaging in personal side projects.

